health.qld.gov.au 2019-12-23

# Privacy | Queensland Health

Queensland Health is committed to protecting user privacy. We understand and appreciate that visitors and users of this web site are concerned about their privacy and the confidentiality and security of any personal information that may be provided to us.

To protect your personal information, Queensland Health staff must follow the privacy principles contained in the [_Information Privacy Act 2009_ (Qld)](https://www.legislation.qld.gov.au/view/html/inforce/current/act-2009-014) (IP Act), which include the nine National Privacy Principles and provisions regarding contracted service providers and the transfer of personal information out of Australia.

These principles contain rules about the collection, use, disclosure, security, quality, access, amendment, storage and openness of personal information.

Staff are also bound by Part 7 of the [_Hospital and Health Boards Act 2011_ (Qld)](https://www.legislation.qld.gov.au/view/html/inforce/current/act-2011-032) (HHB Act) which sets out the duty of confidentiality and exceptions that permit the disclosure of confidential information by ‘designated persons’. Confidential information most often relates to patients of Queensland Health who may be living or deceased.

Queensland Health's [Privacy Plan](https://www.health.qld.gov.au/__data/assets/pdf_file/0027/439164/doh-privacy-plan.pdf) (PDF 380 kB) sets out details of the types of personal information we hold, and how that information is dealt with in accordance with both the _IP Act_ and _HHB Act_. Our Privacy Plan also sets out the process for lodging a privacy complaint and requesting access to personal information, including health records.

In this privacy statement, the Department of Health and the Hospital and Health Services (HHS) are referred to collectively as ‘Queensland Health’. However, the Department of Health and the HHSs each have their own separate Privacy Plans. If you cannot locate a Privacy Plan for a HHS online, you should [contact the relevant HHS](https://www.health.qld.gov.au/system-governance/contact-us/access-info/privacy-contacts) and request they provide you with a copy.

## How is this website monitored?

When you look at this web site, our internet service and analytics providers as well as third party service providers such as a podcast hosting service may make a record of your visit and log the following information for statistical purposes only:

  * the user's server address
  * the user's top level domain name (for example .gov)
  * the date and time of visit to the site
  * the pages accessed and documents downloaded
  * the previous site visited
  * the type of browser used.

No attempt is, or will be made to identify users or their browsing activities except, in the unlikely event of an investigation, where a law enforcement agency may exercise a warrant to inspect activity logs.

## Website analytics

We use Google Analytics (including display advertising features) on our website to gather anonymous information about visitors to our website. When you visit our web pages, your browser automatically sends anonymous information to Google. Examples of the information include the web address of the page that you're visiting, your IP address and demographic information. Google may also use cookies.

We use this data to analyse the pages that are visited, to improve your experience and make sure our website is useful.

You can read more about [how Google uses data](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites). You can choose not to allow Google to collect your information by [opting out of Google Analytics](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) or specifically opt out of [Google Analytics display advertiser features](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads).

## Taking part in Queensland Health surveys

At times you may be asked if you wish to complete survey questionnaires that appear on our site; for example, on topical public health issues such as smoking. Taking part in these surveys is entirely voluntary, and many surveys are able to be completed anonymously.

If you do agree to participate in a survey, you may be asked to review and accept certain additional terms and conditions relating to the use or disclosure of any personal information you provide.

Sometimes, Queensland Health will use web-based survey programs when conducting our surveys. These programs often have servers located overseas (i.e. cloud based computing), and Queensland Health must comply with the _IP Act_ when any personal information is transferred outside of Australia. For more information on our legal obligations in this regard, please see our [Privacy Plan](https://www.health.qld.gov.au/__data/assets/pdf_file/0027/439164/doh-privacy-plan.pdf) (PDF 380 kB).

## Email and feedback information

This is a Queensland Government website. Correspondence received via this site will be treated as a public record and will be retained as required by the _[Public Records Act 2002](https://www.legislation.qld.gov.au/view/pdf/inforce/current/act-2002-011)_ (Qld) and other relevant regulations.

Although every effort will be made, Queensland Health does not guarantee to reply to all correspondence received. Where appropriate, emails sent to this site may be forwarded internally to other business areas within Queensland Health, or to an appropriate Hospital and Health Service for direct response.

Your name and contact details will not be disclosed to other third parties without your consent, unless where the disclosure is authorised or required by or under law. Email messages may however be monitored by our website support staff for system trouble shooting and maintenance purposes.

## Closed Circuit Television (CCTV) surveillance

Camera surveillance operates within Department of Health premises for work-related, health and safety reasons and for the investigation and prosecution of criminal offences.

Footage will only be accessed by persons authorised to do so. Should an incident occur, footage may be provided for law enforcement purposes or civil or criminal proceedings. The CCTV footage will be retained for 90 days. This period may be extended where an incident has occurred or where requested by authorised personnel. Your information will not be given to any other person or agency unless where the disclosure is authorised or required by or under law.

Enquiries regarding CCTV footage operating within Department of Health should be made to the Department of Housing and Public Work by phoning security on +61 7 3234 0777. Enquiries about footage from HHSs should be made directly to the HHS concerned.

## How do I obtain access to information held about me by Queensland Health?

Queensland Health supports your right to see or amend the personal information (including health information) we hold about you. To find out how to access or amend your health records and personal information, or to learn more about how Queensland Health protects your privacy rights, please visit [Health records and privacy](https://www.health.qld.gov.au/system-governance/records-privacy/health-personal). Our [Privacy Plan](https://www.health.qld.gov.au/__data/assets/pdf_file/0027/439164/doh-privacy-plan.pdf) (PDF 380 kB) also sets out some helpful information in this regard.
